# Joshua Delsman

"Josh is an extremely capable individual who's personal drive and motivation to provide simple, well thought out solutions and systems for complex and integral projects have been a key factor to the continuing and future success of the Ultraspeed Group. It's rare to see such attention to detail and pride in one's work in someone of his age. I'm positively refreshed by his attitude to take an active interest in other areas of the business in implementing his

Namuli Katumba Head of Business Development Ultraspeed

development projects."

"Josh is an incredibly talented individual. He's bright, innovative and a pleasure to work with."

Kelly Blanchard Former Traffic Manager Destination Rewards

"Josh is a pleasure to work with and is always on top of his game. He has a vast knowledge of computer and internet related topics and always comes up with viable solutions to complex problems. I would recommend Josh to any other company seeking a dedicated employee."

Randall Amiel Internet Marketing Analyst Destination Rewards 61, Kleine Wharf, 8 Orsman Road, London, N1 5QL, United Kingdom jdelsman@voxxit.com

## **PERSONAL PROFILE**

Highly qualified, senior-level web application developer with over seven years of management and development experience in Internet service industries. Effective leader focused on simplicity, accessibility and ease of use of software. Talent for reversing negative sales trends, creating beautiful, exciting user experiences, and maximising profit and automation in businesses both large and small.

## **EDUCATION**

## Florida Atlantic University - Boca Raton, FL

Partial Computer Science (B.S.) degree - 2008 to 2009

## Suffolk University - Boston, MA

Partial Business & Marketing (B.S.) degree - 2007 to 2008

## William T. McFatter Technical Center - Davie, FL

New Media/Graphic Arts certificate - 2003 to 2007

## **EXPERIENCE**

## Head of Software Development, Ultraspeed - London, UK - 2009 to Current

Designed and developed an enterprise billing/customer management and ordering platform using Ruby on Rails, incorporating over ten different third-party APIs using SOAP and RESTful XML and JSON. Worked with large domain name and SSL certificate providers to assist with their own API development to help meet our needs better. Wrote open-source EPP Ruby gem to interface with domain name registries supporting the standard EPP protocol; used in Ultraspeed operations, and by other companies publicly. Gave successful talks at industry events on the power of Ruby on Rails web development, and how to succeed using it.

#### Senior Web Developer, Destination Rewards - Boca Raton, FL - 2008 to 2009

Worked with Fortune 100 companies to develop incentive/royalty platforms according to their business model, incorporating their branding. Coordinated team of developers to handle front-end tasks on a daily basis, and spearheaded operations which included full-scale enterprise design and Ruby on Rails application development. Frequently trained employees and lead interactive workshops on the best design & development methodologies and best practices.

## Owner, Voxxit - Miami, FL - 2003 to 2008

Responsible for daily operations, including complete wireframing, web design, development, implementation, and quality assurance/testing. Additionally, responsibilities included business development, sales and finance.

## Systems Administrator, Lunarpages - Los Angeles, CA - 2006-2007

Responsible for assisting in monitoring and administration of over 1,000 shared and dedicated servers at a time, concurrently serving over one million customers. Took part in developing Bash and Ruby scripts to assist with repetative administrative tasks. Frequently consulted with enterprise clients for scaling their web presence with clustered environments.

## Web Designer, Site5 Internet Services - Remote - 2005-2006

Redesigned multiple web presences, including the main corporate web site, engineering blog, web control panel for end-users, and several other internal projects.

## "Josh is a creative and motivated team leader. [His] accomplishments and professional presence is comparative to someone who has been in the work force for 20 years. He continually finds ways to implement new concepts and existing concepts

in the work force for 20 years. He continually finds ways to implement new concepts and existing concepts in a more efficient fashion. Always dedicated to the projects at hand and making the best decisions to assist his coworkers and the companies needs. I fully recommend adding Josh to any team that requires growth, he will drive the project to fruition."

## Beatrice Halstead

Marketing/Communications Specialist
Destination Rewards

"Josh has been on several projects I have managed, and he was integral piece to the success of each project. He is great in a team environment, works great under pressure, and has an unbelievable knack for finding creative solutions for complex requirements on projects."

## Charlie Pfeiffer

Project Manager Destination Rewards

"Josh, and Voxxit as a whole, exceeded all of my expectations. The quality of work was wonderful and Josh was inspired and energetic making him a pleasure to work with. The level of professionalism and expertise I encountered will keep me as a client for a long time to come."

## Colleen Morneweck

Former Client
Owner of mybabysbows.com

Read more at:

## http://uk.linkedin.com/in/joshdelsman

## **PROFICIENCIES**

#### Web UI Design

- Hand-coded HTML 4.01 & XHTML I.0 (Strict)
- CSS 1, 2.1 & 3
- Standards Compliancy
- Wireframing
- Designing & Implementing Accessible Web User Interfaces
- E-mail Design & Coding for Web & GUI Clients
- Search Engine Optimisation (SEO)
- Cross-platform Compatibility
- Flash 8+
- A|AX
- Usability Studies

#### Web Development

- JavaScript & ¡Query/Prototype Frameworks
- Ruby
- Ruby on Rails
- Basic Understanding of Java/ISP Principles
- PHP & Smarty
- Git (Preferred)
- CVS
- Subversion
- · Bash Scripting
- MySQL
- XML
- YAML
- JSON (Preferred)

#### ΔΡΙσ

- REST/CRUD API Design (Preferred)
- SOAP

## System Administration

- Mac OS X Client/Server
- Microsoft Windows 2000/2003/XP/NT
- UNIX/Linux (CentOS, RedHat, Debian)
- FreeBSD 4/5
- Web Server Optimisation/Clustering
- cPanel/DirectAdmin/Plesk
- TCP/IP Networking
- BIND DNS Service
- FTP/WebDAV/rsync/SCP
- Apache/LigHTTPd/nginx
- Mongrel
- Passenger/Ruby Enterprise Edition
- Nagios & Zabbix Server Monitoring
- APF/BFD/SIM/Rkhunter (UNIX Security)
- Asterisk PBX/VoIP
- VMware

## Graphic Design/Other

- Adobe InDesign/Photoshop/Illustrator
- Macromedia Dreamweaver
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Customer Relationship Management (CRM)

Code samples are available upon request.